<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Rishika Malli</title>
    <link>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Rishika Malli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 7: Linear SVM versus RBF Kernel SVM Classification</title>
      <link>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>*Let’s start by demonstrating the difference between SVM and Other ML Models: While ML Models tries to learn the stark difference between the Data points in disparate classes, the SVM Algorithm tries to find the most similar characteristics between two data points of these classes (which are our support vectors)
*Linear SVM versus Gaussian Radial Basis Function Kernel SVM: Generally, when the data set is linearly separable, we use Linear SVM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 6: True Salary Detector using Random Forest</title>
      <link>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Random Forest is an Ensemble ML Algorithm used majorly for Regression and Classification problems. Ensemble learning simply put is when you generate &amp;amp; combine multiple different models or the same algorithm multiple times to make it more powerful and solve complex problems. Random Forest builds multiple decision trees and merges them together to get a more accurate prediction. There a various advantages of using Random Forest including Increased Accuracy &amp;amp; Stability of the resulting algorithm, and Easy measurement of relative importance of each factor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 5: Purchase based on Social Network Ads - Logistical Regression</title>
      <link>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>User details such as Gender, Age, and Salary used to classify the purchase of an item presented in Social Network Ads. Predict the future outcomes of purchase given the above details, for targeted marketing and recommendations, using Logistical Classification in R Programming Language. Visualization plot - Green and Tomato Red BG denote classification among Successful Purchase and not respectively based on training set. Highlight Green and Cherry Red points denote the prediction of user&amp;rsquo;s purchase based on test set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Factors that determine Admission - Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Cleansed the data and analyzed the factors that influence the admission of a student into a college from historical data, and determined the key drivers - Scores, LOR, CGPA and Research Performed Regression to find factors majorly affecting admission and also predict the admission of a particular student based on these key factors, using R programming language and Machine learning Optimized Linear and Logistical Regression to reach the best model    Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Prediction of Breast Cancer</title>
      <link>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Project to Predict the likeliness of Breast Cancer by determining the Class of tumor into either Malignant or Benign. (Malignant Tumor indicates the occurrence of Breast Cancer) Performed Linear Regression to Classify the dependent variable (Class) based on various Independent cell factors such as Clump Thickness, Uniformity of Cell size, Cell shape, Bare Nuclei etc. Model Fit Accuracy of 95.62 %    Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: SmartCom for Differently-Abled</title>
      <link>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>A real-time wearable device developed using cost-effective technologies that enable the deaf-blind user to communicate using Malossi language to a common man in the vicinity using GSM Module The Touch gestures is captured and processed into normal text message and speech, and further displayed on an Android Application Technologies used – Python, Java, Raspberry Pi, Sensor Module, Gloves, PuTTY, and Android Application Awarded best Major Outgoing project at Open Day, 2018 BMSIT&amp;amp;M Reviewed &amp;amp; Published at IEEE - 2018 International Conference    Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: NOTE-IT</title>
      <link>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>E-Learning Web Application developed as a substitute for email data sharing of classroom resources - notes and assignments. Teachers can upload the question papers, assignments, and other learning material; Students can share notes and access the uploaded material Technologies used were HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL, Database, and Android Application    Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rishikamalli.github.io/Rishika_Portfolio/post/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can follow me on these social media platforms
   Platform URL     LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rishikamalli   Github: https://github.com/RishikaMalli    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
